

veligeti.murali@gmail.com
+91 9686544544

Bangalore, India

Download Resume

Expert-level Software Architect who has more than 15 years of experience developing proprietary enterprise software products and has optimum excitement in using various technologies to design, develop, and attentively deploy real enterprise class software, including building a knowledge of customer's environments and their use of products. Self motivated with the ability to be proactive with project execution.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Principal Engineer

Endurance International Global

02/2015 - Present

Achivements / Task

- Designed and Developed Microservices and interaction between them.
- Migration of customer profile to Okta. Support both legacy systems which doesn't supports token based authentication as well as newer system which support both Token based systems.
- Collaborated with product management to design, build and test systems
- Collaborated with developers and performance engineers to enhance supportability and identify performance bottlenecks.

Director-Engineering/Senior System Architect

Huawei Technologies India Pvt Ltd

02/2015 - 11/2020

- Achivements / Task
- Designed and Developed Microservices and interaction between them.
- Designed and Created private cloud set using Docker and Kubernetes.
- Worked on SDC ONAP module Developed ETL tool for huge data.
- Developed shared central authentication system in Java/AngularJS for intranet applications.
- Collaborated with product management to design, build and test systems.
- Collaborated with developers and performance engineers to enhance supportability and identify
 performance bottlenecks.
- Contributed Python codebase used in the automated deployment of software on multiple virtual machines
- Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs.
- Created, delivered and maintained scalable system architecture to support a high-availability internet site with various internal applications.
- Performed regression and system-level testing to verify software quality and function before it was released.

Lead Engineer

Nalashaa Solutions LLC

03/2014 - 02/2015

Achivements / Task

- Involved in identifying performance issues and enhance the code to resolve bottlenecks in the customer environment.
- Evaluated multiple software solutions during early software architecture plotting and system migration planning stage.
- Developed Integration Platform for different systems such as SAP and CRM system.
- Optimized the existing application for the customer by implementing web sockets based solution.
- Implemented designs, including experimentation and multiple iterations.
- Diagnosed and troubleshooting UNIX and Windows processing problems and applied solutions to increase company efficiency.
- Provided methodologies for object-oriented software development and efficient database design.
- Designed and implemented new server standards for core business services.
- Recommended architectural improvements, design solutions and integration solutions.
- Used to do lot of research in identifying new technologies and tools for enhancing product value and increasing team productivity.

SKILLS

AWS Cloud Spinnaker

Jenkins Argo CD OKTA

AWS Cloud Spring Boot

Spring Cloud React

Vue.js Angular

Apacii Spark Scala

Python Pandas

Java (J2EE, EJB, JSP, JNI, Servlets, Log4j)

Web Services (SOAP, WSDL, REST API)

Node.js Spring AWS

Olavel Especies

Apache Kafka Rabbit MQ

Hibernate JP/

vveblogie oelvel

Webcenter Portal

Ole 4 Female

Netflix OSS components(Eureka, Zuul, Hystrix)

Huawei Cloud

Microservices Istic

Oracle MySq

IBM Netcool

EDUCATION

O -- - - -

Senior Consultant

British Telecom

05/2013 - 03/2014

Achivements / Task

- Involved in evaluation of multiple solutions and multiple open source products to identify best suitable product for development.
- Involved in developing Use Case document and written High Level Design and Low Level Design.
- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Involved in performance testing to verify software quality and function before it was released.
- Worked closely with other team members to plan, design and develop robust solutions in a timely manner.
- Assessed costs and risks associated with developing new features and products.
- Interacts with Software Vendors Oracle and IBM to solve the problems raised in the product.
- Used tools such as JProfiler and MAT tools to identify performance bottlenecks in the application and revamped the application using the latest technologies such as HTML5 and Emberjs.
- Implemented continuous integration tools in deployment process.

Senior Software Engineer

Oracle India Pvt Ltd

02/2009 - 05/2013

Achivements / Task

- Interact with Portal product/Server product support team, investigating and diagnosing problems, instrumenting code to identify bugs and fixing them in the code level, and providing optimal solutions to the customer.
- Worked on reproducing Production issues on Portal/Server installers and debugging the code to find the fix for the problems.
- Worked on bug fixes in the Portal product related to WSRP 2.0, UCM VCR Adapter, Content Management, DVT (Dynamic Visitor Tools), Personalization, Interaction Management, REST API. DISC API.
- Worked on issues in Server product related to WebApp, JDBC, JMS, Memory Leaks and Performance Issues
- Worked on developing software which helps to collect the logs files from customer environment
 when memory issues comes in production server and also helps in providing possible solutions
 when problem occurs.
- Involved in writing complex logic for server performance to improve. Had rewritten the entire module for JMS performance.
- Involving in managing and maintain code and configurations for all the future and previous version of the product.
- Worked as consultant and involved in onsite engagements for Architecture Design review, Performance Tuning and Development.
- Involved in development Oracle Cloud software.
- Involved in designing, development and testing of features via applications and services.

Software Engineer

IT People Corporation India Pvt Ltd

08/2008 - 02/2009

Achivements / Task

- Evaluated existing applications to reprogram, update and add new features.
- Designed and developed prototypes according to specifications.
- Identified and resolved performance and scaling issues in the existing applications.
- Developed applications with high quality source code within deadlines.

Master Of Engineering ME

Arunai Engineering College [Anna University] 08/2003 - 06/2005

Bachelor Of Technlogy BTech

Arunai Engineering College [University Of Madras] 08/1999 - 04/2003

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

- Involved in developing prototypes to confirm feasibility of the solution.
- Received Director award for performing excellence in Design and development of project for Singtel and
- Top Coder across Huawei India 2017 (For high code contribution with good quality).
- Excellence in Project Delivery 2016 (This award is meant for delivering project with good quality).
- Excellence in Project Delivery 2015 (This award is meant for delivering project with good quality).
- Outstanding Contributor Award for FY10 Q2 (For contributing in the area of Weblogic Portal Knowledge Management. This award has an Executive VP level visibility at Oracle.)
- Spot Award for FY10,
 Q3 (These awards are
 used to recognize
 individuals that have
 demonstrated
 commitment to their
 job and to helping
 others, whether a
 customer or
 teammate.
 Considerations include
 commitment &
 dedication to a goal or
 project and consistent
 high performance.)

OSCAR Award Nominee for Rookie FY10.

Associate - IT Services

Mindtree Pvt Ltd

04/2008 - 08/2008

Achivements / Task

- Collecting information on project and developed some of the use cases.
- Worked on building REST API and code modularization.
- Worked on implementing CI environment which does builds automatically.
- Involved in doing Proof of Concept using Spring/Hibernate and successfully completed.
- Involved in writing High Level Design by considering Use Case document.
- Worked on developing JUNITs and done 100% code coverage.

Software Technical Consultant

CRMIT Solutions Pvt Ltd

05/2006 - 04/2008

Achivements / Task

- Involved in developing prototypes to confirm feasibility of the solution.
- Researched, designed and implemented scalable applications for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing.
- Wrote maintainable and extensible code in a team environment.
- Worked effectively with design teams to ensure software solutions elevated client side experience.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, upgrade interfaces and improve performance.
- Prepared detailed reports concerning project specifications and activities.
- Developed code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches.
- Collaborated with developers and performance engineers to enhance supportability and identify performance bottlenecks.
- Fast in debugging customer problems and provide optimal solutions.

- Star Award for FY11, Q4 (These awards are used to recognize individuals that have demonstrated commitment to their job and to helping others, whether a customer or teammate.
 Considerations include commitment & dedication to a goal or project and consistent high performance.)
- Star Award for FY13,
 Q1 (These awards are
 used to recognize
 individuals that have
 demonstrated
 commitment to their
 job and to helping
 others, whether a
 customer or
 teammate.
 Considerations include
 commitment &
 dedication to a goal or
 project and consistent
 high performance.